<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>David A W Barton</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/</link><description>Recent content on David A W Barton</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cityinthesky.co.uk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Background</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/background/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/background/</guid><description>&lt;p>I focus on the application of scientific machine learning (SciML), particularly physics-based machine learning, to nonlinear dynamics problems coming from engineering. I also have a broad range of research interests across the field of applied mathematics and computer science. I focus particularly on engineering-related applications (e.g., aeroelastic flutter) and I have a sideline in tactile robotics (joint with &lt;a href="https://lepora.com/">Nathan Lepora&lt;/a>). Many mathematicians call me an engineer, whilst many engineers call me a mathematician — you can form your own opinions 😀.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Current research team</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/current-researchers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/current-researchers/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you are interested in working with me, either as a PhD student or a Research Associate (post-doctoral) take a look at my page on &lt;a href="../new-researchers/">opportunities for new researchers&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="current-doctoral-research-students">Current doctoral research students&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.bristol.ac.uk/cdt/interactive-ai/current-students/2022-cohort/shannon/">Andrew Shannon&lt;/a> — working on scientific machine learning in neural dynamics and funded by the Interactive AI centre for doctoral training (started October 2022).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mishaal Sanad — working on inerter-based vibration suppression for pantographs (started December 2021).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://maxyang27896.github.io/">Max Yang&lt;/a> — working on reinforcement learning for tactile robotics and funded by an EPSRC DTP award (started November 2021).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://ddrous.github.io/">Roussel Desmond Nzoyem Ngueguin&lt;/a> — working on scientific machine learning for control of fluid flows and funded by the Interactive AI centre for doctoral training (started October 2021).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Kesheng Wang — working on optimal design of modular multi-level power converters (started October 2021).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Joining the team</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/new-researchers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/new-researchers/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://cityinthesky.co.uk/tags/potential-project">Example PhD projects&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> gives a few suggestions of topics I&amp;rsquo;m interested in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I manage a collaborative and friendly group of researchers who strive to do excellent work at the intersection of applied mathematics, engineering, and machine learning. We work within the larger Engineering Mathematics Research Group and have strong connections to other areas such as the Robotics Research Group, the Dynamics and Control Research Group, and the Computational Neuroscience Research Group. It&amp;rsquo;s a very supportive environment, with researchers going on to a wide range of opportunities including lectureships (e.g., Imperial, Exeter, Glasgow) and industrial careers (e.g., Dyson, Rolls Royce, GraphCore).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>New collaborations</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/new-collaborations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/new-collaborations/</guid><description>&lt;p>Collaborative work is one of the best parts of academic life and my previous collaborations have led to many different contributions and outcomes. Whether hosting visiting PhD students or Professors, or remote work on a topic of mutual interest, I&amp;rsquo;m keen to explore new collaborations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My &lt;a href="../background/">research interests&lt;/a> are quite varied and so there are many opportunities for collaboration. As such, if you are interested in collaborating with me, send me an email and we can discuss the possibilities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Previous team members</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/previous-researchers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/previous-researchers/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="previous-post-doctoral-research-staff">Previous post-doctoral research staff&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Dongxiao Hong — working on uncertainty quantification in hybrid testing and more generally for nonlinear systems funded as part of the EPSRC Programme Grant &lt;a href="https://gow.epsrc.ukri.org/NGBOViewGrant.aspx?GrantRef=EP/R006768/1">&amp;ldquo;Digital twins for improved dynamic design&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a> (May 2022 until July 2023). Went onto a research associate position at Imperial College London.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sandor Beregi — working on control-based continuation and SciML funded as part of the EPSRC Responsive-Mode Grant &lt;a href="https://gow.epsrc.ukri.org/NGBOViewGrant.aspx?GrantRef=EP/P019323/1">&amp;ldquo;Next-generation test methods for nonlinear structures&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a> and, subsequently, by the EPSRC Programme Grant &lt;a href="https://gow.epsrc.ukri.org/NGBOViewGrant.aspx?GrantRef=EP/R006768/1">&amp;ldquo;Digital twins for improved dynamic design&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a> (May 2019 until January 2023). Went onto a research associate position at Imperial College London.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Alessandra Vizzaccaro — working on hybrid testing with uncertainty as part of the EPSRC Programme Grant &lt;a href="https://gow.epsrc.ukri.org/NGBOViewGrant.aspx?GrantRef=EP/R006768/1">&amp;ldquo;Digital twins for improved dynamic design&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a> (November 2020 until December 2022). Went onto a research associate position at the University of Exeter.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.imperial.ac.uk/people/l.renson">Ludovic Renson&lt;/a> — worked on control theory and related aspects control-based continuation (September 2014 until August 2019). Went on to a lectureship at Imperial College.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Irene Tartaruga — worked on control-based continuation as part of the EPSRC Responsive-Mode Grant &lt;a href="https://gow.epsrc.ukri.org/NGBOViewGrant.aspx?GrantRef=EP/P019323/1">&amp;ldquo;Next-generation test methods for nonlinear structures&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a> (May 2017 to December 2018). Went on to work as a Loads and Aerodynamics Engineer at Stirling Dynamics.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="previous-doctoral-research-students">Previous doctoral research students&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Lizzie Stone — Feeling the way: creating versatile tactile robots through online learning for edge following (awarded PhD 23 January 2024).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Kyoung Hyun Lee — Bifurcation-based ordinary differential equation model identification (awarded PhD 24 January 2023). Went on to a research associate position at the University of Auckland.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Kirsty Aquilina — Tactile perception and control of a soft shear-sensitive optical tactile sensor (awarded PhD 24 June 2021). Went on to work as a data scientist at Aptiv (autonomous driving systems).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Adam Zienkiewicz — Data-driven modelling of zebrafish locomotion and collective behaviour (awarded PhD 10 May 2016). Went on to work as a Robotics Engineer at Dyson.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dan Hewitt — Detecting freeplay in mechanical systems (awarded PhD 10 May 2016). Went on to work as a Research Engineer at MASS.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.gla.ac.uk/schools/engineering/staff/andreacammarano/">Andrea Cammarano&lt;/a> — Increasing the bandwidth of resonant vibration-based energy harvesters (awarded PhD 8 January 2013). Went on to a lectureship at the University of Glasgow.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Unlocking the potential of PDE-constrained optimal control: a dive into numerical methods</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/posts/2023/comparison-of-differentiable-programming/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/posts/2023/comparison-of-differentiable-programming/</guid><description>&lt;p>An overview of &lt;strong>&amp;lsquo;A Comparison of Mesh-Free Differentiable Programming and Data-Driven Strategies for Optimal Control under PDE Constraints&amp;rsquo;,&lt;/strong> Roussel D. Nzoyem Ngueguin, David A.W. Barton, Tom Deakin, &lt;a href="https://sc23.supercomputing.org/">SC23, Denver, USA&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.02286">Available on arXiv&lt;/a> or via the &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1145/3624062.3626078">ACM&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A &lt;a href="https://www.doi2bib.org/bib/https://doi.org/10.1145/3624062.3626078">BibTeX reference is also available&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Editorial note:&lt;/em> I&amp;rsquo;ve often intended to create blog posts of papers that I&amp;rsquo;ve been involved with but I&amp;rsquo;ve never managed to make time to do it. However, in the world of ChatGPT we can automatically (and largely accurately) generate them.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Research project: Hybrid modelling and nonlinear dynamics in aircraft design</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/posts/2023/project-aeroelastic-experiments/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/posts/2023/project-aeroelastic-experiments/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This is a potential research project for new research students. It is intended to be a starting point for discussion/further investigation rather than a complete research plan. If you are interested in working with me, see &lt;a href="https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/new-researchers/">opportunities for new researchers&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Keywords:&lt;/em> aeroelastics, scientific machine learning, control-based continuation, nonlinear dynamics&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is a drive towards high-efficiency and high-performance aircraft. This requires lighter and more fuel-efficient structural designs, which are often more flexible than traditional rigid designs. This flexibility can result in disastrous nonlinear behaviour; for example, the destruction of the NASA Helios prototype. This project seeks to develop new approaches to nonlinear behaviour in aircraft and so enable a new generation of low-carbon aircraft.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Research project: Online learning for tactile robotics</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/posts/2023/project-online-learning-for-tactile-robotics/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/posts/2023/project-online-learning-for-tactile-robotics/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This is a potential research project for new research students. It is intended to be a starting point for discussion/further investigation rather than a complete research plan. If you are interested in working with me, see &lt;a href="https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/new-researchers/">opportunities for new researchers&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Keywords:&lt;/em> online learning, machine learning, tactile robotics, generative models&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Machine learning (ML) equips robots with the ability to learn from and adapt to new environments, enhancing autonomy and efficiency in complex tasks. However, many ML approaches rely on extensive data for training. This heavy reliance on large volumes of data can hamstring a robot&amp;rsquo;s ability to function in dynamic real-world conditions—imagine a robotic assistant in a home struggling to recognize new types of objects because it was trained on a limited set of household items. Such data dependency limits the robots&amp;rsquo; effectiveness in diverse real-world applications. We seek to overcome this problem in the context of tactile robotics by exploiting generative online learning, enabling robots to learn &amp;lsquo;in the moment&amp;rsquo; and adapt swiftly to the unpredictability of real-world tasks.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Research project: Surrogate modelling and machine learning for electrical power systems</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/posts/2023/project-surrogate-modelling-electrical/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/posts/2023/project-surrogate-modelling-electrical/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This is a potential research project for new research students. It is intended to be a starting point for discussion/further investigation rather than a complete research plan. If you are interested in working with me, see &lt;a href="https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/new-researchers/">opportunities for new researchers&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Keywords:&lt;/em> surrogate modelling, machine learning, reservoir computing, power electronics&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Designing new devices, particularly in electrical power conversion for renewable energy, is often challenging because of constraints on mass, volume, and cost. Designers must innovate within these boundaries, making trade-offs to meet specifications without compromising performance. This PhD project will employ surrogate modelling and machine learning to improve the efficiency of design processes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>12 month postdoc opportunity in (nonlinear) differential equations</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/posts/2022/digitwins-postdoc/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/posts/2022/digitwins-postdoc/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’ve got a postdoctoral position open at the University of Bristol, UK: &lt;a href="https://www.bristol.ac.uk/jobs/find/details/?jobId=264809">https://www.bristol.ac.uk/jobs/find/details/?jobId=264809&lt;/a>. It’s a one year position that must finish at some point before end June 2023 (end of grant, now extended beyond the date given in the advert). In short I’m looking for someone with experience in (nonlinear) differential equations, ideally engineering background and some interest in uncertainty quantification. (And who programs in Julia, obviously 😀)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The group is small but supportive and work at the interface between (engineering-focused) physical experiments and mathematical methods. We&amp;rsquo;re part of a wider applied mathematics/engineering dynamics research group that covers a wide range of interests.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stability of delay differential equations (DDEs) in Julia</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/posts/2021/stability-of-delay-differential-equations-in-julia/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/posts/2021/stability-of-delay-differential-equations-in-julia/</guid><description>Another in my series of &amp;#39;try not to implement it yet again&amp;#39;, this time on how to calculate the stability of (linearised) delay differential equations.</description></item><item><title>Broad areas for potential projects</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/posts/2021/broad-project-areas/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/posts/2021/broad-project-areas/</guid><description>Here are some (very!) broad areas for possible PhD projects. I haven&amp;#39;t fleshed out any of the details but these are all areas that I&amp;#39;m interested in. Contact me if you&amp;#39;d like to pursue one of them.</description></item><item><title>Collocation for finding periodic orbits of ODEs</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/posts/2020/collocation-for-finding-periodic-orbits-of-odes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/posts/2020/collocation-for-finding-periodic-orbits-of-odes/</guid><description>Computing periodic orbits of ordinary differential equations (ODEs) with collocation is a relatively quick and easy thing to do. Here I demonstrate the method using both Julia and MATLAB with Fourier collocation.</description></item><item><title>Working with broadcasting in Julia</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/posts/2019/working-with-broadcasting-in-julia/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/posts/2019/working-with-broadcasting-in-julia/</guid><description>&lt;p>Broadcasting in Julia is a way of writing vectorised code (think Matlab) that is performant and explicit. The benefits of performant code are obvious (faster!) but explicit vectorisation is also a significant benefit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I first saw Matlab and how you could call the &lt;code>sin&lt;/code> with a vector input, I was (slightly) blown away by the usefulness of this. It didn&amp;rsquo;t take too long for me to realise the limitations though; vectorising a complicated function can require quite a bit of code gymnastics, which doesn&amp;rsquo;t usually help the readability, particularly for those students who are relatively new to programming.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BarycentricInterpolation.jl</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/posts/2018/barycentricinterpolation.jl/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/posts/2018/barycentricinterpolation.jl/</guid><description>&lt;p>Over the past couple of years or so I&amp;rsquo;ve been getting into the Julia programming language; it&amp;rsquo;s been great to watch the language mature over time. Many people proclaim the virtues of its speed (it&amp;rsquo;s very fast for a dynamic language) but really I like its elegance - it&amp;rsquo;s a very well designed language that makes full use of multiple dispatch. (Multiple dispatch is something that I doubt most coders know much about but once you are used to it, it&amp;rsquo;s indispensable!)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/posts/2023/project-active-learning-for-nonlinear-nodes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/posts/2023/project-active-learning-for-nonlinear-nodes/</guid><description>&lt;p>Active learning for neural ODEs with CBC&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>About Me</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/about-me/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/about-me/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m a Professor of Computational and Experimental Mathematics in the &lt;a href="https://www.bristol.ac.uk/engineering/schools/eng-maths-tech/">School of Engineering Mathematics and Technology&lt;/a> at the &lt;a href="https://www.bristol.ac.uk/">University of Bristol&lt;/a>, UK. I’m active in &lt;a href="https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/">research&lt;/a> in nonlinear dynamics and control mixed with scientific machine learning, and a bit of robotics. I&amp;rsquo;m always interested in new collaborations, so take a look at my &lt;a href="https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/">research&lt;/a> pages and get in touch.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m also husband to Johanna and father of Phoebe, Niamh, Esther, Titus, and Charlotte, and spend a lot of time involved in my local church &lt;a href="https://emmanuelbristol.org.uk/bishopston/">Emmanuel Bishopston&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BarycentricInterpolation.jl</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/opensource/barycentricinterpolation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/opensource/barycentricinterpolation/</guid><description>&lt;p>A simple implementation of Barycentric polynomials (interpolation and differentiation) for generic numeric types using &lt;em>Barycentric Lagrange Interpolation&lt;/em> by Berrut and Trefethen (SIAM Review 46, pgs. 501-517) in Julia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Source code available from &lt;a href="https://github.com/dawbarton/BarycentricInterpolation.jl">BarycentricInterpolation.jl&lt;/a> on GitHub.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Christianity</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/christianity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/christianity/</guid><description>&lt;p>At one level, my faith will be considered to be largely irrelevant to many people. However, it shapes every area of my life including my work. (Feel free to ask me how!)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m heavily involved in the &lt;a href="https://emmanuelbristol.org.uk/">Emmanuel Bristol family of churches&lt;/a> and encourage you to check it out if you are ever in Bristol.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Below is a testimony to my faith in Jesus that I wrote over a decade ago.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>PDF2SVG</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/opensource/pdf2svg/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/opensource/pdf2svg/</guid><description>&lt;p>A little program that converges a (page of a) PDF file into a Scalable Vector Graphics (SVG) file which can be opened by Inkscape. It’s nothing more than a simple wrapper over the top of Poppler and Cairo but it turned out to be quite popular since when it was written there were very few other utilities to do the job!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note:&lt;/strong> since this utility was written, the maintainers of &lt;a href="https://poppler.freedesktop.org/">Poppler&lt;/a> have written a utility that works on the same principle: &lt;code>pdftocairo&lt;/code>. I recommend that you use their utility since it is better maintained than mine.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Principles of the UKRIO code of practice for research</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/ukrio-code-of-practice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/ukrio-code-of-practice/</guid><description>&lt;p>Academic life can progress in many different ways. As far as I can, I aim to provide a healthy work environment for all those I interact with. As such, I follow these principles taken from &lt;a href="https://ukrio.org/publications/code-of-practice-for-research/2-0-principles/">https://ukrio.org/publications/code-of-practice-for-research/2-0-principles/&lt;/a> and I strongly encourage others to follow them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>EXCELLENCE:&lt;/strong> organisations and researchers should strive for excellence when conducting research and aim to produce and disseminate work of the highest quality. This Code, its Principles and its Standards are intended to support these goals.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>RTC</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/opensource/rtc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/opensource/rtc/</guid><description>&lt;p>A real-time controller designed around the BeagleBone Black. This low-cost piece of hardware (and associated software) can do the job of much more expensive commercial real-time control offerings (e.g., dSpace), though without a nice GUI interface. Matlab and Python interfaces available.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>See the &lt;a href="https://github.com/dawbarton/rtc/">GitHub page&lt;/a> for the code. If you are interested in the RTC, it&amp;rsquo;s best to get in touch with me as it&amp;rsquo;s not that straightforward.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>