<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>David AW Barton</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/</link><description>Recent content on David AW Barton</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cityinthesky.co.uk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Background</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/background/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/background/</guid><description>For my publications, see my Google Scholar page as Google is better at updating lists than I am!
I have a broad range of research interests across the field of applied mathematics, but I focus particularly on engineering-related applications including robotics. Many mathematicians would call me an engineer, whilst many would engineers call me a mathematician — you can form your own opinions 😀.
I’m more generally interested in the theory/practice underpinning scientific computing and programming.</description></item><item><title>Opportunities for new researchers</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/new-researchers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/new-researchers/</guid><description>If you are looking for a PhD projects, see my posts with the potential-project tag. Most of the projects are fairly broad in scope so there is plenty of room to define your own directions, though occasionally I&amp;rsquo;ll post more restrictive projects when the funding source is more prescriptive. I&amp;rsquo;ve got some funding information below for both PhD and post-doctoral researchers to answer some common questions I get. Feel free to drop me an email with your CV if you are interested in any of the projects or have other (related) ideas of your own.</description></item><item><title>Current researchers</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/current-researchers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/current-researchers/</guid><description>If you are interested in working with me, either as a PhD student or a Research Associate (post-doctoral) take a look at my page on opportunities for new researchers.
Current post-doctoral research staff Dongxiao Hong — working on uncertainty quantification in hybrid testing and more generally for nonlinear systems funded by as part of the EPSRC grant &amp;ldquo;Next-generation test methods for nonlinear structures&amp;rdquo; (May 2022 until June 2023). Current doctoral research students Mishaal Sanad — working on inerter-based vibration suppression for pantographs (started December 2021).</description></item><item><title>Previous researchers</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/previous-researchers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/previous-researchers/</guid><description>Previous post-doctoral research staff Sandor Beregi — working on control-based continuation and SciML funded by as part of the EPSRC grant &amp;ldquo;Next-generation test methods for nonlinear structures&amp;rdquo; (May 2019 until January 2023). Went onto a research associate position at Imperial College. Alessandra Vizzaccaro — working on hybrid testing with uncertainty as part of the EPSRC grant &amp;ldquo;Digital twins for improved dynamic design&amp;rdquo; (November 2020 until December 2022). Went onto a research associate position at the University of Exeter.</description></item><item><title>12 month postdoc opportunity in (nonlinear) differential equations</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/posts/2022/digitwins-postdoc/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/posts/2022/digitwins-postdoc/</guid><description>I’ve got a postdoctoral position open at the University of Bristol, UK: https://www.bristol.ac.uk/jobs/find/details/?jobId=264809. It’s a one year position that must finish at some point before end June 2023 (end of grant, now extended beyond the date given in the advert). In short I’m looking for someone with experience in (nonlinear) differential equations, ideally engineering background and some interest in uncertainty quantification. (And who programs in Julia, obviously 😀)
The group is small but supportive and work at the interface between (engineering-focused) physical experiments and mathematical methods.</description></item><item><title>Stability of delay differential equations (DDEs) in Julia</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/posts/2021/stability-of-delay-differential-equations-in-julia/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/posts/2021/stability-of-delay-differential-equations-in-julia/</guid><description>Another in my series of &amp;#39;try not to implement it yet again&amp;#39;, this time on how to calculate the stability of (linearised) delay differential equations.</description></item><item><title>Broad areas for potential projects</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/posts/2021/broad-project-areas/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/posts/2021/broad-project-areas/</guid><description>Here are some (very!) broad areas for possible PhD projects. I haven&amp;#39;t fleshed out any of the details but these are all areas that I&amp;#39;m interested in. Contact me if you&amp;#39;d like to pursue one of them.</description></item><item><title>Collocation for finding periodic orbits of ODEs</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/posts/2020/collocation-for-finding-periodic-orbits-of-odes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/posts/2020/collocation-for-finding-periodic-orbits-of-odes/</guid><description>Computing periodic orbits of ordinary differential equations (ODEs) with collocation is a relatively quick and easy thing to do. Here I demonstrate the method using both Julia and MATLAB with Fourier collocation.</description></item><item><title>Working with broadcasting in Julia</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/posts/2019/working-with-broadcasting-in-julia/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/posts/2019/working-with-broadcasting-in-julia/</guid><description>Broadcasting in Julia is a way of writing vectorised code (think Matlab) that is performant and explicit. The benefits of performant code are obvious (faster!) but explicit vectorisation is also a significant benefit.
When I first saw Matlab and how you could call the sin with a vector input, I was (slightly) blown away by the usefulness of this. It didn&amp;rsquo;t take too long for me to realise the limitations though; vectorising a complicated function can require quite a bit of code gymnastics, which doesn&amp;rsquo;t usually help the readability, particularly for those students who are relatively new to programming.</description></item><item><title>BarycentricInterpolation.jl</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/posts/2018/barycentricinterpolation.jl/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/posts/2018/barycentricinterpolation.jl/</guid><description>Over the past couple of years or so I&amp;rsquo;ve been getting into the Julia programming language; it&amp;rsquo;s been great to watch the language mature over time. Many people proclaim the virtues of its speed (it&amp;rsquo;s very fast for a dynamic language) but really I like its elegance - it&amp;rsquo;s a very well designed language that makes full use of multiple dispatch. (Multiple dispatch is something that I doubt most coders know much about but once you are used to it, it&amp;rsquo;s indispensable!</description></item><item><title>About Me</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/about-me/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/about-me/</guid><description>Who I am, what I do, and how to contact me.</description></item><item><title>BarycentricInterpolation.jl</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/opensource/barycentricinterpolation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/opensource/barycentricinterpolation/</guid><description>A simple implementation of Barycentric polynomials (interpolation and differentiation) for generic numeric types using Barycentric Lagrange Interpolation by Berrut and Trefethen (SIAM Review 46, pgs. 501-517) in Julia.
Source code available from BarycentricInterpolation.jl on GitHub.</description></item><item><title>Christianity</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/christianity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/christianity/</guid><description>At one level, my faith will be considered to be largely irrelevant to many people. However, it shapes every area of my life including my work. (Feel free to ask me how!)
I&amp;rsquo;m heavily involved in the Emmanuel Bristol family of churches and encourage you to check it out if you are ever in Bristol.
Below is a testimony to my faith in Jesus that I wrote over a decade ago.</description></item><item><title>PDF2SVG</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/opensource/pdf2svg/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/opensource/pdf2svg/</guid><description>A little program that converges a (page of a) PDF file into a Scalable Vector Graphics (SVG) file which can be opened by Inkscape. It’s nothing more than a simple wrapper over the top of Poppler and Cairo but it turned out to be quite popular since when it was written there were very few other utilities to do the job!
Note: since this utility was written, the maintainers of Poppler have written a utility that works on the same principle: pdftocairo.</description></item><item><title>Principles of the UKRIO code of practice for research</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/ukrio-code-of-practice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/ukrio-code-of-practice/</guid><description>These are taken from https://ukrio.org/publications/code-of-practice-for-research/2-0-principles/ and I strongly encourage others to follow them.
EXCELLENCE: organisations and researchers should strive for excellence when conducting research and aim to produce and disseminate work of the highest quality. This Code, its Principles and its Standards are intended to support these goals.
HONESTY: organisations should work to create and maintain a culture of research that fosters and supports honesty in research. Researchers should be honest in relation to their own research and that of others.</description></item><item><title>RTC</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/opensource/rtc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/opensource/rtc/</guid><description>A real-time controller designed around the BeagleBone Black. This low-cost piece of hardware (and associated software) can do the job of much more expensive commercial real-time control offerings (e.g., dSpace), though without a nice GUI interface. Matlab and Python interfaces available.
See the GitHub page for the code. If you are interested in the RTC, it&amp;rsquo;s best to get in touch with me as it&amp;rsquo;s not that straightforward.</description></item></channel></rss>