<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Research on David A W Barton</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/</link><description>Recent content in Research on David A W Barton</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Background</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/background/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/background/</guid><description>For my publications, see my Google Scholar page as Google is better at updating lists than I am!
I have a broad range of research interests across the field of applied mathematics and (physics-based) machine learning, but I focus particularly on engineering-related applications including robotics. Many mathematicians would call me an engineer, whilst many would engineers call me a mathematician — you can form your own opinions 😀.
I’m more generally interested in the theory/practice underpinning scientific computing and programming.</description></item><item><title>Opportunities for new researchers</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/new-researchers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/new-researchers/</guid><description>I manage a collaborative and friendly group of researchers who strive to do excellent work at the intersection of applied mathematics, engineering, and machine learning. We work within the larger Engineering Mathematics Research Group and have strong connections to other areas such as the Robotics Research Group, the Dynamics and Control Research Group, and the Computational Neuroscience Research Group. It&amp;rsquo;s a very supportive environment, with researchers going on to a wide range of opportunities including lectureships (e.</description></item><item><title>Current researchers</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/current-researchers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/current-researchers/</guid><description>If you are interested in working with me, either as a PhD student or a Research Associate (post-doctoral) take a look at my page on opportunities for new researchers.
Current doctoral research students Andrew Shannon — working on scientific machine learning in neural dynamics and funded by the Interactive AI centre for doctoral training (started October 2022). Mishaal Sanad — working on inerter-based vibration suppression for pantographs (started December 2021). Max Yang — working on reinforcement learning for tactile robotics and funded by an EPSRC DTP award (started November 2021).</description></item><item><title>New collaborations</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/new-collaborations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/new-collaborations/</guid><description>Collaborative work is one of the best parts of academic life and my previous collaborations have led to many different contributions and outcomes. Whether hosting visiting PhD students or Professors, or remote work on a topic of mutual interest, I&amp;rsquo;m keen to explore new collaborations.
My research interests are quite varied and so there are many opportunities for collaboration. As such, if you are interested in collaborating with me, send me an email and we can discuss the possibilities.</description></item><item><title>Previous researchers</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/previous-researchers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/previous-researchers/</guid><description>Previous post-doctoral research staff Dongxiao Hong — working on uncertainty quantification in hybrid testing and more generally for nonlinear systems funded as part of the EPSRC Programme Grant &amp;ldquo;Digital twins for improved dynamic design&amp;rdquo; (May 2022 until July 2023). Went onto a research associate position at Imperial College London. Sandor Beregi — working on control-based continuation and SciML funded as part of the EPSRC Responsive-Mode Grant &amp;ldquo;Next-generation test methods for nonlinear structures&amp;rdquo; and, subsequently, by the EPSRC Programme Grant &amp;ldquo;Digital twins for improved dynamic design&amp;rdquo; (May 2019 until January 2023).</description></item><item><title>Principles of the UKRIO code of practice for research</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/ukrio-code-of-practice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/ukrio-code-of-practice/</guid><description>Academic life can progress in many different ways. As far as I can, I aim to provide a healthy work environment for all those I interact with. As such, I follow these principles taken from https://ukrio.org/publications/code-of-practice-for-research/2-0-principles/ and I strongly encourage others to follow them.
EXCELLENCE: organisations and researchers should strive for excellence when conducting research and aim to produce and disseminate work of the highest quality. This Code, its Principles and its Standards are intended to support these goals.</description></item></channel></rss>