<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Research on David A W Barton</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/</link><description>Recent content in Research on David A W Barton</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.147.5</generator><language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Background</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/background/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/background/</guid><description>&lt;p>I focus on the application of scientific machine learning (SciML), particularly physics-based machine learning, to nonlinear dynamics problems coming from engineering. I also have a broad range of research interests across the field of applied mathematics and computer science. I focus particularly on engineering-related applications (e.g., aeroelastic flutter) and I have a sideline in tactile robotics (joint with &lt;a href="https://lepora.com/">Nathan Lepora&lt;/a>). Many mathematicians call me an engineer, whilst many engineers call me a mathematician — you can form your own opinions 😀.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Current research team</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/current-researchers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/current-researchers/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you are interested in working with me, either as a PhD student or a Research Associate (post-doctoral) take a look at my page on &lt;a href="../new-researchers/">opportunities for new researchers&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="current-doctoral-research-students">Current doctoral research students&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Yidong Qiu — working on the nonlinear dynamics of whirl flutter in the context of eVTOL aircraft (started February 2025, co-supervised by Djamel Rezgui).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ningyuan Xu — working on scientific machine learning in the context of engineering biology and funded by a CSC scholarship (started January 2025, co-supervised with Lucia Marucci).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Jun Wang — working on control-based continuation for experimentally investigating the nonlinear dynamics of a Hawk aircraft model (started September 2024, co-supervised with Mark Lowenberg).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Wenhao He — working on multi-modal deep reinforcement learning for tactile robotics and funded by a CSC scholarship (started September 2024, co-supervised with Nathan Lepora).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Brian Siu — working on machine learning for modelling material properties in nuclear fusion and co-funded by the UK Atomic Energy Authority and an EPSRC DTP (started September 2024, co-supervised with Burcu Tasdemir).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.bristol.ac.uk/cdt/interactive-ai/current-students/2023-cohort/raines/">Jonny Raines&lt;/a> — working on an AI-based generative design assistant for engineers can make use of standard components as well as free-form design and funded by the Interactive AI centre for doctoral training (started October 2023, co-supervised with Ben Hicks).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.bristol.ac.uk/cdt/interactive-ai/current-students/2022-cohort/shannon/">Andrew Shannon&lt;/a> — working on scientific machine learning in neural dynamics and funded by the Interactive AI centre for doctoral training (started October 2022, co-supervised with Conor Houghton and Martin Homer).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.bristol.ac.uk/cdt/interactive-ai/current-students/2022-cohort/field/">Harry Field&lt;/a> — working on the use of large language models for the design of reward functions for reinforcement learning in tactile robotics and funded by the Interactive AI centre for doctoral training (started October 2022, co-supervised with Nathan Lepora).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://maxyang27896.github.io/">Max Yang&lt;/a> — working on reinforcement learning for tactile robotics and funded by an EPSRC DTP award (started November 2021, co-supervised with Nathan Lepora).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://ddrous.github.io/">Roussel Desmond Nzoyem Ngueguin&lt;/a> — working on scientific machine learning for control of fluid flows and funded by the Interactive AI centre for doctoral training (started October 2021, co-supervised with Tom Deakin).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Kesheng Wang — working on optimal design of modular multi-level power converters (started October 2021, co-supervised with Ian Laird).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Joining the team</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/new-researchers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/new-researchers/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://cityinthesky.co.uk/tags/potential-project">Example PhD projects&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> gives a few suggestions of topics I&amp;rsquo;m interested in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I manage a collaborative and friendly group of researchers who strive to do excellent work at the intersection of applied mathematics, engineering, and machine learning. We work within the larger Engineering Mathematics Research Group and have strong connections to other areas such as the Robotics Research Group, the Dynamics and Control Research Group, and the Computational Neuroscience Research Group. It&amp;rsquo;s a very supportive environment, with researchers going on to a wide range of opportunities including lectureships (e.g., Imperial, Exeter, Glasgow) and industrial careers (e.g., Dyson, Rolls Royce, GraphCore).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>New collaborations</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/new-collaborations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/new-collaborations/</guid><description>&lt;p>Collaborative work is one of the best parts of academic life and my previous collaborations have led to many different contributions and outcomes. Whether hosting visiting PhD students or Professors, or remote work on a topic of mutual interest, I&amp;rsquo;m keen to explore new collaborations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My &lt;a href="../background/">research interests&lt;/a> are quite varied and so there are many opportunities for collaboration. As such, if you are interested in collaborating with me, send me an email and we can discuss the possibilities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Previous team members</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/previous-researchers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/previous-researchers/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="previous-post-doctoral-research-staff">Previous post-doctoral research staff&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Dongxiao Hong — worked on uncertainty quantification in hybrid testing and more generally for nonlinear systems funded as part of the EPSRC Programme Grant &lt;em>Digital twins for improved dynamic design&lt;/em> (EP/R006768/1; May 2022 until July 2023). Went onto a research associate position at Imperial College London.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sandor Beregi — worked on control-based continuation and SciML funded as part of the EPSRC Responsive-Mode Grant &lt;em>Next-generation test methods for nonlinear structures&lt;/em> (EP/P019323/1) and, subsequently, by the EPSRC Programme Grant &lt;em>Digital twins for improved dynamic design&lt;/em> (EP/R006768/1; May 2019 until January 2023). Went onto a research associate position at Imperial College London.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Alessandra Vizzaccaro — worked on hybrid testing with uncertainty as part of the EPSRC Programme Grant &lt;em>Digital twins for improved dynamic design&lt;/em> (EP/R006768/1; November 2020 until December 2022). Went onto a research associate position at the University of Exeter.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Qicheng Zhang — worked on the nonlinear behaviour of auxetic foams as part of the EPSRC Digital Manufacturing Grant (EP/R032793/1; from September 2019 until March 2022). Went onto a research associate position at the University of Swansea.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Tatsuki Fushimi — worked on nonlinear control of particles using ultrasonic levitation (March 2020 until May 2020). Went onto a tenure-track position at the University of Tsukuba, Japan.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.imperial.ac.uk/people/l.renson">Ludovic Renson&lt;/a> — worked on control theory and related aspects control-based continuation (September 2014 until August 2019). Went on to a lectureship at Imperial College.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Irene Tartaruga — worked on control-based continuation as part of the EPSRC Responsive-Mode Grant &lt;em>Next-generation test methods for nonlinear structures&lt;/em> (EP/P019323/1; May 2017 to December 2018). Went on to work as a Loads and Aerodynamics Engineer at Stirling Dynamics.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="previous-doctoral-research-students">Previous doctoral research students&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Lizzie Stone — Feeling the way: creating versatile tactile robots through online learning for edge following (awarded PhD 23 January 2024). Went on to be a software engineer at Renishaw.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Kyoung Hyun Lee — Bifurcation-based ordinary differential equation model identification (awarded PhD 24 January 2023). Went on to a research associate position at the University of Auckland.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Kirsty Aquilina — Tactile perception and control of a soft shear-sensitive optical tactile sensor (awarded PhD 24 June 2021). Went on to work as a data scientist at Aptiv (autonomous driving systems).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Adam Zienkiewicz — Data-driven modelling of zebrafish locomotion and collective behaviour (awarded PhD 10 May 2016). Went on to work as a robotics engineer at Dyson.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dan Hewitt — Detecting freeplay in mechanical systems (awarded PhD 10 May 2016). Went on to work as a research engineer at MASS.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.southampton.ac.uk/people/65cs99/professor-andrea-cammarano">Andrea Cammarano&lt;/a> — Increasing the bandwidth of resonant vibration-based energy harvesters (awarded PhD 8 January 2013). Went on to a lectureship at the University of Glasgow.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Principles of the UKRIO code of practice for research</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/ukrio-code-of-practice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/ukrio-code-of-practice/</guid><description>&lt;p>Academic life can progress in many different ways. As far as I can, I aim to provide a healthy work environment for all those I interact with. As such, I follow these principles taken from &lt;a href="https://ukrio.org/publications/code-of-practice-for-research/2-0-principles/">https://ukrio.org/publications/code-of-practice-for-research/2-0-principles/&lt;/a> and I strongly encourage others to follow them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>EXCELLENCE:&lt;/strong> organisations and researchers should strive for excellence when conducting research and aim to produce and disseminate work of the highest quality. This Code, its Principles and its Standards are intended to support these goals.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>