<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Research on David AW Barton</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/</link><description>Recent content in Research on David AW Barton</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Background</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/background/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/background/</guid><description>For my publications, see my Google Scholar page as Google is better at updating lists than I am!
I have a broad range of research interests across the field of applied mathematics, but I focus particularly on engineering-related applications including robotics. Many mathematicians would call me an engineer, whilst many would engineers call me a mathematician — you can form your own opinions 😀.
I’m more generally interested in the theory/practice underpinning scientific computing and programming.</description></item><item><title>Opportunities for new researchers</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/new-researchers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/new-researchers/</guid><description>If you are looking for a PhD projects, see my posts with the potential-project tag. Most of the projects are fairly broad in scope so there is plenty of room to define your own directions, though occasionally I&amp;rsquo;ll post more restrictive projects when the funding source is more prescriptive. I&amp;rsquo;ve got some funding information below for both PhD and post-doctoral researchers to answer some common questions I get. Feel free to drop me an email with your CV if you are interested in any of the projects or have other (related) ideas of your own.</description></item><item><title>Current researchers</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/current-researchers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/current-researchers/</guid><description>If you are interested in working with me, either as a PhD student or a Research Associate (post-doctoral) take a look at my page on opportunities for new researchers.
Current post-doctoral research staff Dongxiao Hong — working on uncertainty quantification in hybrid testing and more generally for nonlinear systems funded by as part of the EPSRC grant &amp;ldquo;Next-generation test methods for nonlinear structures&amp;rdquo; (May 2022 until June 2023). Current doctoral research students Max Yang — working on reinforcement learning for tactile robotics and funded by an EPSRC DTP award (started November 2021).</description></item><item><title>Previous researchers</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/previous-researchers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/previous-researchers/</guid><description>Previous post-doctoral research staff Sandor Beregi — working on control-based continuation and SciML funded by as part of the EPSRC grant &amp;ldquo;Next-generation test methods for nonlinear structures&amp;rdquo; (May 2019 until January 2023). Went onto a research associate position at Imperial College. Alessandra Vizzaccaro — working on hybrid testing with uncertainty as part of the EPSRC grant &amp;ldquo;Digital twins for improved dynamic design&amp;rdquo; (November 2020 until December 2022). Went onto a research associate position at the University of Exeter.</description></item><item><title>Principles of the UKRIO code of practice for research</title><link>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/ukrio-code-of-practice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cityinthesky.co.uk/research/ukrio-code-of-practice/</guid><description>These are taken from https://ukrio.org/publications/code-of-practice-for-research/2-0-principles/ and I strongly encourage others to follow them.
EXCELLENCE: organisations and researchers should strive for excellence when conducting research and aim to produce and disseminate work of the highest quality. This Code, its Principles and its Standards are intended to support these goals.
HONESTY: organisations should work to create and maintain a culture of research that fosters and supports honesty in research. Researchers should be honest in relation to their own research and that of others.</description></item></channel></rss>